Witness the creation.
Making Squid Game: The Challenge is a documentary film directed by None.
Go behind the scenes and witness how the "Squid Game"-inspired reality show
transformed from a scripted drama to a cutthroat, nail-biting competition.
Self, played by Nicola Brown.
Self, played by Rikki Finlay.
Self, played by Tim Harcourt.
Self, played by Toni Ireland.
Self, played by Stephen Lambert.
Self, played by Rich Leist.
Squid Game (Korean: 오징어 게임; RR: Ojingeo geim) is a South Korean dystopian adult survival thriller
drama television series created, written, and directed by Hwang Dong-hyuk for Netflix.
The series revolves around a secret contest where 456 players, all of whom are in deep financial hardship, risk their lives to play a
series of children's games that result in death if eliminated, for the chance to win a ₩45.6 billion (US$39.86 million) prize.
The series' title draws from ojingeo ("squid"), a Korean children's game.
Lee Jung-jae, who portrays series protagonist
Seong Gi-hun, leads an ensemble cast.
Hwang conceived the idea based on his own economic struggles, as well
as the class disparity in South Korea and capitalism.
Although he wrote the story in 2009, Hwang could not find a production company to fund the idea until Netflix
took an interest around 2019 as part of a drive to expand their foreign programming offerings.
The first season of Squid Game was released worldwide on September 17,
2021, to critical acclaim and international attention.
It became Netflix's most-watched series and received numerous accolades,
including six Primetime Emmy Awards and one Golden Globe.
The second season was released on December 26, 2024, followed by the
third and final season released on June 27, 2025.
The final two seasons were filmed back-to-back and met with generally positive
reviews from critics, though were considered inferior to the first season.
Since its release, Squid Game has become one of Netflix's flagship shows.